Alright
Let's refactor the code for our audio in this lesson
and the hardware audio code
This refactoring will be the final result
First, the current code structure is like this
We have the audio input
and the audio output as two separate components
Essentially, these two components are integrated for use
Since we have both audio input and output
They basically appear simultaneously.
Can we combine them into one?
Yeah, merge them into a single component.
This type has already been encapsulated for us.
The component is this one.
This component here.
Let's take a look at the current structure.
Our current code.
The structure of this code is as follows.
Let's take a look.
Zoom out a bit.
Currently, our structure looks like this.
This is our audio equipment layer.
That is, this code, right?
The ES7210 point CPP.
This is the driver layer for the audio input device.
And then,
we wrote an abstraction layer for audio input.
Right?
We've written this part as well.
And for the audio output device, um,
The device driver layer is structured like this.
It's this ES8311 dot CPP file.
But we mentioned that the audio output abstraction layer,
We haven't written it yet.
If you want to write it yourself,
You might also need to write an audio abstraction layer.
So we're going to combine these two into one, right?
But for now, we won't write this one.
We'll use this component.
We'll use this overall component.
Regarding this component,
it's provided by Espressif official.
Let's take a look.
Let's see which chips this component supports.
It supports a lot of chips.
We've integrated these chips into this module.
Like our ES8311 chip,
and the ES S7210.
Both are included here.
And the ES S8311 chip,
it supports both playback and recording.
But we only use its playback function.
The ES7210 only supports recording.
Meaning it only handles audio input.
We're using these two chips.
So, this component is supported, right?
Now, let's take a look at its architecture.
Here's a preview of it.
First, this is the ESP32-S3.
It's the USB32 module we're using.
And
it uses the E48311 here as an example.
to illustrate the point.
Because it supports a microphone.
Does it support AABC?
So, he used this as an example.
This one replaces the yes, um.
7210.
It replaces two, functioning as both audio input and output.
So, its architecture is like this.
The DAC is for output.
It provides the amplifier chip.
Then here it's a 3-2 configuration.
This S3 has a gear for the amplifier.
It's the enable pin.
We have that as well.
The enable pin controls it.
Ultimately, it outputs to the loudspeakers.
The microphone is right here.
Actually, you can add a diagram.
And it abstracts a lot of things.
There are many layers of abstraction inside.
We don't need to worry about how many layers are abstracted.
We only focus on what matters to us.
Ultimately, we provide ES7210 to them.
And ES8311 as well.
Some settings for the drivers of these two chips
Ultimately, they abstract it to this level for us.
We use this layer exclusively.
This is what we ultimately use.
The anonymous abstraction layer is this.
Let's then take a look at how we use it.
Let's have a look.
Inside here,
the first one is configuring the audio input and output channels.
This is similar to when we operated the ESP,
the ES7210 and ES8311.
The initialization process for these two chips is pretty much the same.
Ultimately, it will generate a handle.
It refers to one of its inputs.
It's for receiving and sending handles.
This is like when we've already initialized it.
Once we get this handle,
we send it over,
and it generates a data interface handle for us.
We call this function,
This handle, on one hand, is for the audio output here.
This generates a handle for the audio output device.
These two are simultaneously provided to the function to create a
It creates an output device for
the audio output device instance.
This is the abstraction layer.
And ultimately, it generates a handle for the abstraction layer.
The handle
is then ultimately provided to the abstraction layer structure.
Ultimately, we use these abstraction layers.
Here, fixing the electrical performance is like packaging all these things you see together.
Packaging these more complex scenarios,
various elements,
various parameters, once packaged together,
what we see for the higher-level calls,
is these open and close functions, right?
the red ones are these uh,
open, close, read, and write, right?
this read is for input, right?
Audio input
Then the output is audio
It's quite simple
It's obvious just by looking at it
What does this mean?
We don't need to worry about the hardware layers
We don't need to care about them
So this is the component that does the work for us
Of course, we need to complete these modules step by step
Some initialization
We are using these two chips
We can package these two chips into a module
To create a new module
If other boards also use these two chips in the future
They can directly reuse this module
That's how it works
In the next lesson, we'll start completing these step by step
Initialization and all that
This ultimately provides us with this abstraction layer
We use this abstraction layer for audio
Input and output
That's it